YUE WANG

GitHub: https://github.com/josephwang1993 • Cell: 647 869 2268 • josephwang1993@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities.

Portfolio: https://josephwang1993.github.io/

Skills

- Agile/Scrum methodology
- Self-starter and quick-learner
- Troubleshooting and debugging
- Write clear documentation
- Strong problem solver

- Proficient in Java, JavaScript, Python
- JQuery, ReactJS, Angular 2+ and MarkoJS
- Node.js, Webpack
- SQL, MongoDB
- AWS experience

Education

Bachelor of Applied Science and Engineering: Computer Engineering, 2017 **University of Toronto - St. George Campus** - Toronto, ON

Work History

Full Stack Developer, 06/2017 to 06/2018

Leonardo Worldwide Corporation – Toronto, ON

- Tech Stack: Java/JavaScript/MySQL/AWS/MarkoJS
- Wrote Terraform scripts to manage artifacts in AWS S3 buckets.
- Worked with MySQL database in development
- Provided support for customer support team to resolve client issues to save overall waiting time.
- Wrote code that's unit-tested, well-documented as per business requirements to facilitate final delivery.
- Learnt and used the frontend framework MarkoJS and SASS that's used in the frontend team to build a new website theme.

Software Developer Intern, 05/2015 to 08/2016

Densify – Markham, ON

- Tech Stack: Java/JavaScript/MSSQL/Dojo/Jaspersoft Studio
- Learnt how the product worked by fixing bugs in both frontend and backend.
- Implemented new REST APIs in Java to adapt to new business requirements.
- Wrote and debugged SQL queries in order to fill values into the Business Intelligence report.
- Participated in building Business Intelligence report with TIBCO Jaspersoft Studio.

Projects

Recent projects can be seen on my GitHub account: https://github.com/josephwang1993

Multiuser Chatroom

Personal Project, 08/2018

- Tech stack: React / Redux / Nodejs / SocketIO
- Built a chatroom with React
- Used Redux to manage the state of the app (system messages and user chat messages)
- Used SocketIO in backend Node server to relay user messages
- Demo is at https://ebchatroom.herokuapp.com

Multi-modal Travel Planner

Capstone Project , 12/2016 to 04/2017

- Tech stack: React / Webpack / Nodejs
- Worked with a team to build a web-based map application for UofT CVST (Connected Vehicles and Smart Transportation) that gives recommendations on routes from a place to another by combining all possible travel modes
- Developed frontend with React and Webpack
- Responsible for backend Node server maintenance
- Strengthened problem solving skills by continuously discussing with other developers on websites such as StackOverflow

Event Sharing Social Web App

Web Programming Course Project, 09/2016 to 12/2016

- Tech stack: JQuery/Nodejs/MongoDB
- Involved in designing and developing a social web application where people can share events and make friends with each other

- Participated in the backend Node server development, including REST API implementation and MongoDB operations
- Enhanced the app's security by introducing Passport.js, a popular third-party authentication middleware for Nodejs